ABHINAV VYAS

Product Designer

abhinav.uxdesign@gmail.com

Portfolio: Abhinav-UX-Portfolio

PROFILE

I am a Product Designer having 1.3 Years of Professional & Freelancing experience. Ambitious and always willing to learn, grow and become better everyday. I enjoy conducting user research and designing smooth experiences by practicing Design Thinking, and User Centered Design and by using Principles of HCI.

Recently completed my UX & Interaction Design Apprenticeship in a Pune based company wherein, I got in-depth exposure of working in collaboration with in-house teams be them other designers as well as developers or other cross-functional teams, and made Design & Development decisions unanimously.

SKILLS

I have a decent experience working individually as well as working with a team to brainstrom and whiteboard concepts. I can create wireframes at varying levels of fidelity, and enjoy prototyping ideas. Also, I confidently use the skills I gained during my previous profession of being a Legal Parliamentary Reporter, such as Stenography for note-taking during or after a user interviews to compile and organise the Qualitative Research data.

Softwares that I'm familliar with:

- Figma
- Figjam
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe XD
- Slack (for Communication)
- Notion (for Productivity)
- Google Workspace
- Miro (for Whiteboarding)
- Marvel App
- Whimsical

Skills as a Product Designer

- Communication & Collaboration
- Interaction Design
- Wireframing & Sketching
- · Iterative Mindset
- Prototyping
- User Psychology
- Decent Knowledge of CSS Box Model
- Agility
- · Ability to Unlearn
- Storyboarding & Storytelling.

Interests

- Transcendental Meditation
- Mobile Photography
- Psychology
- Travelling & Cooking
- Slow Book Reading
 Reading
- Playing Badminton
- Learning new design trends

WORK EXPERIENCE

Coditas Solutions LLP. (Pune, MH)

July, 2022 - Oct, 2022

Associate UX Designer (Apprenticeship)

- Assisted team members in various levels of design & helped in conducting UX research, surveys & interviews.
- Made the process of User Interviews extracted data from interview recordings easier by using my lifelong Stenography & Typing Skills, and reduced time and company's cost by 11-15%
- Contributed in Analysing research results, brainstorming sessions, additional research & Collaboratively made user personas, empathy maps, journey maps, task flows, user flows & storyboards & used other UX/Product Frameworks as needed.
- Made wireframes on different levels, Paper, mid & high fidelity & prototyped them using softwares like Marvel & Figma.
- Did quick fixes on small but critical ux issues (usability & interaction) for various client projects, and helped my senior team members to focus on more serious & critical tasks.
- Solved a Critical CTR Problem for one of our Client's SAAS Product, and was able to hike the CTR by 37% & user conversation rate by 11%.
- Helped deciding in visual design schemes and elements, typography & compositions.
- Efficiently & Proficiently helped the design team by making **Static Components, Interactive Components, UI Elements from scratch** keeping in mind the client brand's consistency & guidelines and **contributed in making Scalable Design Systems.**
- Involved in making final designs by learning & keeping in mind the CSS Box Model and technical constraints. used grid systems and guidelines to align the elements properly on the screen we're designing for.
- Involved in recruiting participants for usability testings. **Did usability testings** and also became observer in Usability Testing and interviews to better understand the user's mind.
- successfully **collaborated with design team, development team and other cross-functional teams** during the process, and filled the communication gap between teams to a great extent.
- Last but not least, I used my knowledge from the ongoing HCI program by Georgia Tech, to level up my design decisions.

Freelance UX/UI Designer

Sept, 2021 - May, 2022

- Consulted a local Media Agency & designed a QR Code Based Progressive Web Application for a Fine-Dining Restaurant based in our Home Town, allowing guests/customers to view Food Menus and to give Written & Voice feedback (Future Scope POS Integration) (NDA)
- Worked with a USA Based client as a UX/UI Designer and designed a website for Automotive Industry. Website was about a Product i.e. On-Board Dygnostic System (OBD-II) Scanner for Cars.
- Made UI Components in Figma, Prototyped screens, solved small ux problems for clients.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology via EDx

Aug, 2022 - Present

CS-6750 (Human Computer Interaction) MOOC (Prof. Dr. David Joyner)

My learnings (so far)

- The overall goals of human-computer interaction and the relationship between HCl, user experience design, human factors engineering, and psychology & the relevance of HCl to domains like healthcare, education, Fintec Etc.
- The emerging ideas in HCl research, such as context-sensitive computing, gesture-based interaction, and social computing using three main views of user in HCl: the Processor, Predictor, and Participant.
- The feedback cycle in user interaction, including gulfs of execution and evaluation.
- The strengths and limitations of the human user, including sensation and memory.
- The role of design principles and heuristics in user interface design.

Google UX Design via Coursera

July, 2021 - Feb, 2022

Designed my First Conceptual Movie Ticket Booking Application to help users deal with sudden movie plan
drops after paying full ticket amount & introduced a new Payment Checkout feature called "Pay at Box Office"
with certain terms and conditions, by following the whole UX Process from conducting user interviews to
making pixel perfect hi-fi Interface design using 8 PX Grid System, and lastly iterated again based on usability
testina.

Bachelors of Arts via JNVU, Jodhpur.